So there's something else?
Yeah.
There's a wind blowing.
Okay.
We are going to call the order, the regular council meeting for today's date and time.
I'm on to this public input and the scheduled personal appearances.
Anyone on the on to us to address the council?
Item three is the consent agenda.
Staff is recommending items four through 15.
Which are claims, minutes, budget amendments, and then all of the utility easements that we just approved.
As well as an agreement between attackers for fit testing.
Any, if there are no questions on any of those items four through 15, I'll give you just a matter
of look because that's a lot of items.
Chief, would you build just kind of a little more items that you've got on here for the ball?
Maybe just give everybody an educator by the little girl.
Yes.
Okay.
Which one is this now?
Item seven.
Seven.
Item five.
15 years ago, a whole bunch of SCBA and bringing models.
They were all back.
It's got models.
And we used to steal.
We've gone to compulsive.
The life of the compulsive models is 15 years.
Instead of 20, even impiders that test it ever by after the third time.
They were like, do the hands a week got by.
Twelve models to the final service recently because they're at the end of that live span.
And we're going to order six now and then at the end of the budget order six more.
Just, you know, five of your plan order to place them as we get it.
Okay.
And the deposit of a lot lighter as a benefit of the area in the SCBA.
So you're not, at this time, you're not down on bottles.
You should be replaced once they come in and they'll build a discard of the six.
We do need bottles.
But we're not down on them.
We've got bottles in the pack.
We've got some spares on the truck.
But we also have some empty holes.
Right.
And then they'll try and we work with bottles with them.
They won't.
So that's all you said.
Okay.
Good.
Do you want to get that on?
Yes.
Any other items?
Any questions on?
Okay.
So we have mostly approved items.
And four, five, six and eight through 15 of them is part of the consent agenda.
I'll make the motion.
And I'll second that.
Bro, call please.
Western.
All right.
Should.
I.
Or get.
For a stir.
And then do we have a motion to approve item seven.
I'll second that.
For a stir.
Should.
I.
Or get.
Item 16.
All right.
Except.
Project.
Vid.
See 18.
12.
For street improvement.
Mill and overlay.
And approve contract.
contingent on submission.
Required documents.
And approve city manager.
does it need to sign a notice to proceed.
So, last fall, I guess we talked about this coming in a little while.
So, Austin gave me any cordial budget streets and we gave recommendations on which streets
could take a mill and overlay that actually had base under and more and that they had been.
So, we got that narrow down.
There was more than the budget allowed.
So, we're kind of focusing on the schools in the hospital and this approach back.
So, this is kind of a south half and then a few more of the north.
We opened beds last week.
We had two bitters.
One was Henry Sappen's son's.
He's got a spring field and then A and A asphalt out of front camera.
So, Henry Sappen came in low.
A little over one and a half million.
And then A and A was at two and a half million.
So, one and a half million.
But it is well under and here's estimate.
That's what we actually probably have more than an entire country.
Which we're excited about.
It was talking about maybe having to fold the A and A ramps out and do them in here's technology.
We didn't see horses.
But with the prices we've got, you should be able to keep all of that in one shot.
And Sean, how did they come in a million dollars less than their competitor?
So, Henry Sappen is going to be in town.
This spring because they're thinking contract at the $20.
$20.
Okay.
And Sappen is working under Henry Sappen during the country.
So, he's already here.
So, the mobilization costs.
This is a non-project.
This is an odd project because we've never designed with it.
The contractor is one of your partners away out of the cryptocurrency.
So, we've been here in probably a lot more comfortable with what's out there.
And we're going to be able to pay the $20.
It's possible.
And we're looking through the bid tab.
I mean, Sappen's roughly half the price.
So, when you say there's no design, what about specs?
So, we're going to use the exact same specs we're using for central.
Okay.
That keeps everybody up to current.
Instead of having your own city's case.
So, we're using the same as calling it.
It's not central.
It's the same concrete.
They still have to be a big guidelines.
We're going to work with the contractor to design before we go to this step.
And make sure we work in a normal price.
But that design goes back on to the contract.
I can see the variance being quite a bit more obvious.
Because the argument is quite obvious.
These are the streets we're going to go north on.
You're going to mill it over like some.
Some of them if you get a soft spot,
you're going to have to take that out,
where they send people.
So it's kind of, we'll see what happens.
So when you say variance, do you mean that there may be some increases in the cost?
I don't think so.
I mean, we've got to go on the end there.
As far as paid in and stuff, it's by the story yard.
So I want you to cover this area,
and we're going to run as far as that goes.
Hope we estimate it high with a lot of this stuff.
Because there's no surveys.
It's an assumed quantity for all the intersections.
What's going to take for sidewalks, right?
I'm sorry.
Drunking down, turning out,
so hopefully we're high on our quantities that come back.
See if we can have the project,
or if we, at quantity, it's more than that.
Do you feel very comfortable doing the scale down version?
The question is, can you do more
and cause of the original amount budget for it?
Right.
And that's something we'd like to look into,
maybe we'll get into the project.
We'll see how things are going.
We're hoping the industry can pretty soon
and we can get that out on the street.
We can see where that budget comes in.
We'd like to get all three of these done.
This is a good policy.
We can get that done.
We can get it.
Inrecept it, ask if there was potential
to do more payment.
That being this job that there's ended in price.
So I told him that something is going to be discussed.
When you get in the project, we'll see.
That would also be put out for bid, though.
Right.
I mean, we might assume that if he doesn't have to mobilize,
he would be pretty aggressive again.
But it's a separate enough project.
It would be put out for bid.
The main street's being rebate.
But the additional payings that could be done for a change order.
That's the project's generic enough.
We could do that.
You would have to approve it.
Yeah.
You would have to approve the change order in quantity.
And we'd come back and talk to you.
Just if that's an offer on the tables.
Any questions for Sean or Tyler?
That's good news.
Great news.
We also rush to get a tea tonight because we want to get all this work done.
And get the asphalt laid as soon as the weather allows.
Yeah.
We'd like to get through contract.
It's going to be possible.
So hopefully, when in resapsed,
I already know the end of your central.
They can work on this stuff.
Do you think you're bouncing the tree?
Two projects.
Everybody in this summer.
I'm going to open it.
Okay.
And this is in conjunction already.
Kevin with our.
Our streets.
What are our guys doing with their equipment?
Yeah.
Filling holes.
Yes.
We've actually started some in-a-half streets on heart.
That we're tearing up.
We're going to rebuild ourselves in half.
And in this whole time, we'll still run the pot and we'll patch your cut-out spots, doing what we can in the house by these run, yes.
And part of an example of that additional form here, we get the base down, and we get that back to end, and we get that back to end.
We might talk a little bit about this next week, we're going to be talking about some of our parts projects, and all that, and we're trying to pull in the house,
because one of the concerns we have is that we have this large project, we've got central, and we've got main, which once that's done, our next day on streets, we're going to be pretty much gone.
Now, we still have the transfer from them as you weigh in all that, so we're going to have to transfer or kind of go more from these larger projects that we've been out, projects that we take care of in-house.
So we're still going to be talking about an annualized budget of anywhere between $5,600,000 a year, but we're going to have to stretch that money, and that's why streets are like haunted, that normally they're not highly traveled streets, or anything, but they're in horrible condition, and we're going to even get back into the shape that we can actually go in and do the work themselves and just buy the materials to take care of it.
Is the parking lot for the splash pad? Is that on a drawing board somewhere?
The current parking lot will be refanished with the splash pad. It's part of that project.
What about over-park? I mean, I see when it first opens, we're going to have a lot of people there, and we had trouble when it was Eagle pitcher finding a parking space.
Are there planes for that? Well, hoping right now the overflow would use the baseball field, and we're hoping to have a walk bridge at that exact time.
That time it opens.
Yeah.
And it kind of gets them off that main street, and it gets them coming from that backside.
We have a game of playing with it.
Any other questions on the street project?
Okay. You look for motion.
So we need to accept staff recommends a way to accept the bid and approve the contract.
Okay. We have motion for 16.
You do?
And local please?
I work at Worcester.
Hi.
I'm 17 new business. Any new business, anyone?
I'm 18 to staff reports. Any questions for staff?
19 is mayor and council committee announcements.
Any announcements on anyone?
That's the next week's art.
Centennial week at NEO.
So on Monday we're inviting community out to do an aerial photo.
We're taking them 100.
I thought I'd be able to let me in, and then we'll do 11, 30, and do a K-cutting ceremony.
It's only $3.
Yeah.
That's a good deal.
So, thank you.
Thank you.
City manager communication.
Four hours of water break up.
One was good.
I sent everybody an email from FEMA about the LOMR maps, the flood maps, which is becoming
a reality.
What I made in the mail and what I make to the community is that it kind of brings to
all the time.
I don't know why we're having this issue.
Some of these fights with GRDA, because this is the very real reality to my amount on what's
happening with our flood maps going up because of our experience with flooding intent.
So, you know, with what we're doing there, what we're doing in regard to FERC.
Sometimes you have to take a step back and read a letter like that and realize this is why we're doing this
battle.
So, just wanted to remind everybody about that, it's going to affect quite a bit of us.
Also, next week, we do have a study session.
And we have three items.
We're wanting to talk to you about some items that Kevin has and just who has about our parts and some kind of
different ways of looking at our parts.
We have a safety center update.
You know, okay, this is permission to start working on that.
A lot of work is already going to take place.
I think, by the next time we're together, we'll have met with I.
I said I'm going to take my first field trips.
So, we're kind of moving right along on that.
I want to bring you up to speed.
And also, GRDA is handling their electric rates in a different manner.
And it might require a change in our ordinance and how we do our electric rates and has longer
electric costs to our customers.
So, we've also been making a presentation about that next week as well.
So, those are items that are pretty important.
So, just want to make sure that we remember that we did have that study session at 430 here.
Next Tuesday.
That's where we're going to start.
Okay.
God.
Any questions for day-to-day in the Olympics?
Can you stop?
Okay.
I have a 21st term.
I don't know.
Did you hear me all the way down?
I think it's one of the side of the road.
Okay.
Let's see.
Do I need to be present?
Which, I appreciate?
For a sticker.